-Misato's in the truck in front of us?
-Yeah.
Okay, why don't you drink
some tea to relax.
Thanks.
If you can drive up next to it,
I'll look in and check.
If it's true, then this is serious.
I'm sorry, Mr. Yashiro.
I could just be wasting your time
playing detective.
What do you mean?
We're pretending
there's some kidnapper out there,
so we've been making friends with any girl
we see off by themselves.
It's to prevent any potential kidnappings
from happening.
You're doing the right thing, then.
It's an effective strategy.
But as a result,
I basically used Misato like bait.
Satoru. I've come to really respect
your proactiveness and mentality.
Is that why you've suddenly become
more outgoing?
Yeah, I felt like I wanted
to fill the void inside.
Both in others and myself.
I feel the same way, Satoru.
It's my life philosophy.
Crap.
That's something Yashiro told us in the
first timeline for our graduation.
Hey, Satoru.
There's no need for you to feel
any guilt or shame right now.
The reason people do anything
is to compensate for their own faults.
That goes for both good deeds
and bad deeds.
The motivation is the same.
That's a pretty extreme way of thinking.
I've actually
done a lot of things lately in order
to get closer to a certain person.
Sometimes I'd be direct,
other times I'd use
some really dirty tricks.
It was really fun.
Is it someone you have feelings for?
I suppose you could compare it to romance.
I mean, it's about filling a void
in both cases.
Want me to get you some candy?
Thanks.
But there isn't any candy in there.
SLEEP AID
LAXATIVE
That's because...
this isn't my car.
Don't worry.
Misato isn't in that truck.
YAMOTO FARM
Satoru, do you ever feel
like your happiest moment
is something that gets
constantly renewed?
You know, mine was just renewed today.
Satoru.
You lied to me about one thing.
You were doing everything knowing
there was a kidnapper in this town.
Right?
I didn't want to believe it.
Someone that could anticipate
my every action.
But it was clear.
The day I gave you and your mother a ride
was the day I was going to
put my plan into action.
That was the second time you
stopped a plan of mine after Kayo.
That's when I began to think
it wasn't just a coincidence.
And so I decided to use Misato as bait.
Satoru, if you showed up for Misato,
my suspicion would turn to conviction.
That you were my enemy.
This can't be happening.
This time, all of the pieces fell right
into place, just as I planned.
I gave Misato tea mixed with laxatives.
Koichi! You don't get food if you lose!
I ordered lunches from the Shiratoris.
SHIRATORI FOODS
RESTROOM
EMERGENCY EXIT
-Satoru? What's up? The bathroom's--
-Mr. Yashiro, great timing!
There's something
I have to check right now.
And now you're here.
This is me in my true form.
I'm such an idiot.
I didn't even suspect him at all.
By trusting Yashiro,
I was trying to
eliminate him from suspicion.
But...
the real killer
is the man next to me.
Gaku Yashiro.
Honestly, it was exhilarating
to have my back against the wall.
It's as if you've seen the future.
Satoru.
I had a brother
who was two years older than me.
He was a violent one.
I got punched every day.
It was because both of my parents
doted on me.
Parental neglect
created a void inside him.
And even as a child,
I understood what he was doing
was to try and fill that void.
Eventually, my brother replaced beating me
with sexually molesting young girls.
-There's this really neat book.
-Oh, really?
Make sure you keep watch, Gaku.
-Let's go.
-Okay.
THE SPIDER'S THREAD
Keeping them from talking
was also my job.
Here, this is for you.
I made sure to do a good job.
I did what I had to do.
And when I was in seventh grade,
it happened.
Until then, nobody had ever
come near that building.
If someone got close,
it was also part of my job
to let him know.
Brother?
Brother?!
Brother...
Is she...?
I couldn't have her yelling.
I didn't have a choice.
This is your fault!
This happened
because you didn't keep watch!
Come on, help me carry her.
Hurry up!
In that moment,
I realized what I had to do.
I made my decision.
FORENSIC MEDICINE
Having killed a young girl, guilt
tragically drove my brother to suicide.
Police forensics ruled out murder.
The case was closed.
That's when I realized...
that my brother was inside me, too.
And that I was looking to fill my void.
You know full well, don't you, Satoru?
Just what that entails for me.
But now it's game over, Satoru.
For you.
And for me.
Your actions should be commended.
My plan and preparation, too.
We both deserve something
for our hard work.
What you will be getting
is peace for this town.
That's what you wanted, isn't it?
And what I will be getting is a death
by my hands, just for myself.
I've decided to leave this town.
That makes a happy ending for both of us.
Isn't that right, Satoru?
Satoru?!
Kids.
I have some very sad news.
Last night,
a car carrying Satoru Fujinuma
was in an accident.
Satoru is currently in critical condition.
He's being treated in the hospital's ICU.
Everyone,
Satoru is coming back.
Let's all pray...
for his safe recovery.
Why, Satoru?
Why?
MIKOTO ELEMENTARY
Here is your cheeseburger set
and croquette set.
That will be 1100 yen.
Out of 2000 yen.
Here is 900 yen in change.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Sawada...
We could've talked back at my place.
I wanted it to be just the two of us.
So, what is it?
Do you feel like...
you're not allowed to enjoy yourself?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
You should go out and have fun.
Do I look that bad?
No, that's not what I meant.
I'm just saying...
you should let loose once in a while.
THE WANDERERS EXHIBIT
UENO ART MUSEUM
It's in Ueno?
Hey. I just want you to remember.
You can actually...
make it to Ueno on one train.
What did he mean by that?
Nothing.
MANABU NISHIZONO
You're the lawyer
Takanari Kobayashi's son,
Kenya, aren't you?
I'm Sawada, a journalist.
When you were in grade school,
I worked for TV Ishikari's News Division.
Then... you know about the incident.
Come to my office with me,
young Kobayashi.
Today... is when the statute
of limitations is up for the case
your father took
involving the murder of the little girl.
We mostly narrowed down the suspects.
But still...
I couldn't find any conclusive evidence.
It's because...
I wasn't good enough.
So, what are you going to do now?
Are you going to give up?
-I can't let things end here.
-In that case...
do you want to find
the real killer with me?
Okay.
I'm home.
It was hot again today, huh?
Satoru.
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto